http://www.algonquincollege.com/policies/privacy/

Site Index
Maps
Skip to content (Press ENTER)
Algonquin College Privacy Statement
Algonquin College (the “College”) is committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information. The College at all times collects, uses and discloses personal information in accordance with the Freedom of Information and Personal Privacy Act, R.S.O. 1990, c. F.31 (“FIPPA”), and under authority of the Ontario Colleges of Applied Arts and Technology Act, 2002, S.O. 2002, c. 8, Sched. F, and other relevant legislation. The College’s personal information handling practices are set out in more detail in its Policy AD02: Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy.
The College is required to disclose personal information such as Ontario Education Numbers, student characteristics and educational outcomes to the Minister of Training, Colleges and Universities under s. 15 of the Ministry of Training, Colleges and Universities Act, R.S.O. 1990, Chapter M. 19, as amended. The ministry collects this data for purposes such as planning, allocating and administering public funding to colleges, universities and other post-secondary educational and training institutions and to conduct research and analysis, including longitudinal studies, and statistical activities conducted by or on behalf of the ministry for purposes that related to post-secondary education and training. Further information on how the Minister of Training, Colleges and Universities uses this personal information is available on the ministry’s website.
Further information on the collection and use of student-level enrolment-related data can be obtained from the Government of Ontario or Ministry of Training Colleges and Universities website http://www.tcu.gov.on.ca/ (English) or http://www.tcu.gov.on.ca/fre/ (French) or by writing to the Director, Postsecondary Finance Branch, Postsecondary Education Division, 7th Floor, Mowat Block, 900 Bay Street, Toronto, ON M7A 1L2
The College collects personal information at several points of contact. It collects personal information from prospective students during marketing and recruitment campaigns, and during the application process. It collects personal information from current students at various times and in various ways throughout their tenure with the College. It may collect personal information from alumni after their tenure at the College. It collects personal information from staff at various times and in various ways in the course of the employment relationship.
Personal information is collected and used for a number of reasons. In the case of prospective students, information is collected and used primarily for the purpose of making admissions-related decisions, including initial contact with the student, the creation, processing and maintenance of student applications, acceptance and registration with the College. In the case of students whose applications are accepted, and current students of the College, information collected before or after enrollment is also collected for the purposes of administering the student’s studies at the College, and to assist the College in providing academic and other services to the student. Information collected from prospective or current students before or after enrollment may also be used for the purposes of statistical analysis, research and marketing. It may also be aggregated, linked to other data, or otherwise used by the College for the purposes of reviewing, improving and developing College programs, policies, and recruitment strategies, measuring program performance and assessing future program needs. In the case of College staff, information is collected primarily for the purpose of managing the employment relationship.
Personal information may also be used or disclosed for purposes reasonably consistent with these purposes. Specific purposes for the collection of information will be set out at the time of collection where required and where distinct from the above. If no purpose is indicated, the information is collected and will be used for the above purposes, or purposes reasonably consistent with those set out above, subject to the provisions of FIPPA.
The College will use or disclose personal information where reasonably necessary to achieve the purposes for which it was collected, or where authorized or required by law to do so. The College may also make available personal information, as required, to third parties who provide services reasonably necessary to the College’s operations, or to the achievement of the purposes stated above. On occasions, personal information may be collected, used and/or disclosed in jurisdictions outside of Ontario. Personal information in different databases in the custody or control of the College may also be linked or aggregated in order to achieve the purposes set out above.
By providing your personal information to the College, you consent to the use or disclosure of personal information as set out above and to the extent necessary to fulfill these purposes. You have a right to withdraw your consent to the use or disclosure of your personal information, however this may have an impact on the College’s ability to provide services to you, including in the case of current students your ability to continue in your studies at the College. Students wishing to withdraw consent in full or in part to the use or disclosure of their personal information should contact the FOI Coordinator for more information on the consequences of withdrawing consent.
The College will take all reasonable measures to safeguard personal information in its control, including but not limited to physical, technical, and operational measures. The College will require, by contract or otherwise, that any third party service provider to whom personal information is transferred has adequate policies and safeguards in place to protect that information. The College will ensure that information which is disposed of in accordance with College policies and all applicable regulations is destroyed securely and in a manner which protects the privacy of the information holder.
You have a right of access to your personal information in the control of the College, subject to the terms of FIPPA and its regulations. To make such a request, or if you have Questions about this Statement or about the College’s personal information practices please contact:
Freedom of Information Coordinator
1385 Woodroffe Avenue, Room C548,
Ottawa, Ontario, K2G 1V8.
FOIcoordinator@algonquincollege.com
Telephone 613-727-4723 Ext. 6407
If you have a complaint about the College’s handling of your personal information, please contact the FOI Coordinator. If your complaint is not resolved to your satisfaction, FIPPA provides a mechanism for independent review by contacting the Information and Privacy Commissioner of Ontario.
Updated: 2016.02.24
Sidebar
Related LinksDownload Policy TemplateAbout Ontario CollegesOntario Colleges of Applied Arts and Technology ActQuestions? Contact us at policies@algonquincollege.comor (613) 727-4723 ext 5192.
This site uses cookies to offer you a better browsing experience. Find out more on how we use cookies and how you can change your settings.
OK
